<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Taylor Carpenter</title>
    <description>BS/MS Dual Degree Student in Computer Science at RIT</description>
    <link>http://taylorcarpenter.me</link>
    <atom:link href="http://taylorcarpenter.me/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Thesis Progress - Defense Announcement</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It has been a while since the previous post, but tomorrow the thesis defense will be announced. A completed and mostly final draft of the report is now available and linked from the thesis page.--more-- Work now focuses on finishing the presentation and then practicing for the defense.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://taylorcarpenter.me/Thesis_Progress_11/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://taylorcarpenter.me/Thesis_Progress_11/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Thesis Progress - Discussion Progress</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The results section of the report has been complete in an initial draft. Current work is focused on the discussion section. Ideally a large portion of the remaining work will be completed over the next few days.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://taylorcarpenter.me/Thesis_Progress_10/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://taylorcarpenter.me/Thesis_Progress_10/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Thesis Progress - Analysis Completed</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It has been a little while since the last update. Life has become somewhat busier the past few weeks so progress has slowed. The final statistical tests were completed on the performance data, TLX assessments, and model accuracies. Subsequently, the study portion of the results section has been completed as an initial draft.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://taylorcarpenter.me/Thesis_Progress_9/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://taylorcarpenter.me/Thesis_Progress_9/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Thesis Progress - Defense Push Back</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The defense date for the thesis has been pushed back. The majority of the report has been drafted and the active research has concluded. The new timeline is the end of October / beginning of November. Work and updates will be slower over the next few months as writing and review continues.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://taylorcarpenter.me/Thesis_Progress_8/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://taylorcarpenter.me/Thesis_Progress_8/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Thesis Progress - Beginning of the End</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;All the data that was collected has been processed into a feature file. Multiple models have already been generated but a few more are still going. The random forest models have all been completed, while the neural networks are only half done. --more--At this time I am beginning to write the final thesis report. Even though the models are not entirely complete, there are other sections of the report that can be done without that information. Time is running out so this will be a compressed writing process.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://taylorcarpenter.me/Thesis_Progress_7/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://taylorcarpenter.me/Thesis_Progress_7/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Thesis Progress - Study Complete</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The data collection portion of the research has been completed. In the end, data from seven participants was collected. One participant was forced to leave the study before completion due to personal reasons. Two other participants were generating poor data due to issues with sensor placement --more--( cranial size was not taken into account when selecting participants ) and a difficulty descrepency with respect to the tasks. Performance summaries and NASA TLX records have been created for each participant. While statistics have not been calculated yet, the trends seen by eye follow what was expected. Currently work is being done on scripts for the data processing, leveraging work done in my previous research with similarly formatted data. While slightly behind schedule as of now, hopefully that time can be made up within the next few days.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://taylorcarpenter.me/Thesis_Progress_6/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://taylorcarpenter.me/Thesis_Progress_6/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Thesis Progress - Study Update</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The study has been going well. Currently, four participants have finished completely, five participants are partially finished, and the final participant begins tomorrow. The data collection should be concluded by the end of the week. --more--While models have not been generated yet, the subjective workload as reported by the participants aligns with the intended study design. Work is being done on scripts to display the performance metrics of each task in a more easily readable manner.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://taylorcarpenter.me/Thesis_Progress_5/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://taylorcarpenter.me/Thesis_Progress_5/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Thesis Progress - The Study Begins</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The study has been approved by the Human Subjects Research Office and work began yesterday. After some trouble with sensors not connecting correctly, everything is now running smoothly. The amount of data being produced is quite large.--more-- After an initial pilot study, a few changes were made to the RanTask configurations and the tasks as a whole. Each trial is now only 10 minutes, rather than 15. This still produces a large amount of data and results in less fatigue on the participants. It was found that conditions 1 and 2 of RanTask were too similar and did not correctly induce varying levels of workload. As such, the conditions were reworked, with condition 1 counting a single tone, condition 2 counting two tones, and condition 3 counting three tones. This makes the task substantially harder, but the goal is not to have a task that everyone can complete, rather to induce different workload levels.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://taylorcarpenter.me/Thesis_Progress_4/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://taylorcarpenter.me/Thesis_Progress_4/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Thesis Progress - Sensor Systems</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The data logger for the heart rate sensor has been completed and is working well. This means that both sensor systems are ready and working for the study. The heart rate sensor being used is ANT+ capable so a small receiver is being used for communication between the computer and the sensor.--more-- The logging script is actually running in a virtual linux machine because the USB libraries necessary for Python to work well with the ANT library are not available for OS X. A C++ program was used in my previous study but the communication was unreliable and not suitable for an extended study. For the EEG sensors, the Emotiv Testbench application will be used to do the recording. This makes the system less streamlined but it is more reliable. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://taylorcarpenter.me/Thesis_Progress_3/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://taylorcarpenter.me/Thesis_Progress_3/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Thesis Progress - Defense Date Change</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A schedule has been added to the website that will be kept up to date. The schedule in the proposal will not be changed as the proposal remain consistent with what was submitted. The thesis defense has been shifted back a day due to a scheduling conflict.--more-- This update has been reflected in the posted schedule. As tasks are completed, they will be crossed off the schedule.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://taylorcarpenter.me/Thesis_Progress_2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://taylorcarpenter.me/Thesis_Progress_2/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>